Amber Jansen

A persistent, determined and adaptable web developer, who enjoys creating and maintaining responsive websites. Having strong problem solving skills, with a readiness and eagerness to learn, developed by keeping up to date with coding best practices, and building websites. Motivated, reliable, able to work to deadlines and enjoys working in a team, demonstrated by previous work experience, working closely with people.

EDUCATION

Self taught web developer

September 2019 - Current

Front end web developer primarily utilising javascript, html 5, Sass, CSS, Gatsby, Graphiql and React, WCAG, Bootstrap

My portfolio — Gatsby | ReactJS | SCSS | Graphiql

Portfolio site designed and coded from scratch to showcase my skills and past work.

Annette's Art — Gatsby | ReactJS | SCSS | Graphigl

Explore beautiful, eye catching Urban Artwork. With a creative and responsive design in mind, with mobile layouts and menu, a combination of CSS grid and flexbox were used. Graphql queries add to this by loading the optimal size of image for each device size and screen resolution.

Weather website — Javascript | CSS

Users can use this application to check the weather in any location, pulling in data from Open Weather Apps API which displays updated real time weather forecasts. Dynamically swaps background images and icons depending on the weather type.

Gifspot — Javascript | CSS

Gifspot allows users to explore the best and newest gifs, straight from GIFFY's API, it returns the most relevant GIFs based on a user's search query, and also has the ability of pulling in more data when the user scrolls to the end of the page.

Chesterfield College, Chesterfield — NVQ Level 2 in Hairdressing

September 2010 - July 2012

Practiced skills with peers as well as providing treatments for paying customers in a commercial setting.

TECHNICAL-SKILLS

HTML5

Javascript

SASS/CSS

Responsive

Web-Design

Bootstrap

Web accessibility/

WCAG.

React

Gatsby

Graphiql

HOBBIES

Keyboard, I love music

Yoga, for focus and increased mobility

Dancing, with friends and at classes

EXPERIENCE

Wadsley News, Hillsborough, Wadsley Lane — Shop Assistant

JULY 2016 - PRESENT

Providing an efficient and friendly service to customers, through answering customer queries, replenishing stock and keeping the shop tidy and welcoming. Other responsibilities include handling money and organising deliveries.

Ant Marketing, City Center, Dereck Dooley — Call Agent

JULY 2013 - 2015

Enthusiastic telesale representative, able to grasp new concepts quickly, experienced with sales, customer service and education. Tasked with projecting a professional company image through phone interaction with new and existing clients. Main duties include problem solving, up-selling, making appointments for engineers and keeping record of the outcome of each call

Mint, Totley, Wadsley Lane — Hairdressing

JULY 2012 - 2013

Hair stylist, with attention to detail, skilled at studying facial features and hair condition, providing fashionable and elegant hairstyles, creating the desired look. Built up a clientele base by ensuring each client's requirements were met, effectively developing lasting interpersonal relationships by helping the clients maintain a professional look at home. Remaining well-prepared and working to limited time frames.